准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
捉水母
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
现在是裤头村的清晨
It is the early morning in bikini bottom
此时水母们正在奔忙着
when the jellyfish are buzzing about
采着水母酱
making their jellyfish jelly
这是怎么了
What is happening here?
捉水母的吗
Collectors?
我好像捉到了
I think I got it
不  等一下
No, wait a minute
跑
Go
嗨  章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
我们在捉水母
We're jellyfishing
那当然了
Of course you are
再见
Bye, now
别走
Wait
我们特地给你做了一张网
We made a net especially for you
想跟我们一起来吗
Do you want to come with us?
真的
Really?
跟你们一起捉水母
Jellyfishing with you guys?
在我看来  今天简直是最美好的一天
That would be the best day ever in my book
我好想去捉水母
I would love to go jellyfishing
我想不出
I can't think of
休息日期间有什么更想做的事
anything I'd love to do more on my day off
能比去捉水母更有趣
than go jellyfishing
尤其是跟我最好的两个朋友
with my two best friends
海绵宝宝还有
SpongeBob and
派大星
Patrick
对
Right
但我就是不行  拜拜
But I can't, bye-bye
下次
Next time?
好
Sure
对
Right
随你们便
Whatever
除非太阳打西边出来
Like that'll ever happen
你也知道  派大星
You know, Patrick
好像章鱼哥从来没有时间玩
it always seems like Squidward never has time for fun
大概是他不喜欢我们吧
Maybe he doesn't like us
不  你在开什么玩笑
No, are you kidding?
我们可是他最好的朋友
We're his best friends
捉水母
Jellyfishing
这就去
I'll go
我还真把他们耍得团团转
I sure had them going
笨水母  快滚
Stupid jellyfish, beat it
朋友
章鱼哥回来了
Squid's back
喂
Hello
派大星
Hey, Patrick
章鱼哥回来了
Squid's home
要保证他被他两个最好的朋友欢迎
and we're going to make sure
he's greeted by his two best friends
那太棒了  他们谁啊
Oh, great, who are they?
我们
Us
出发吧
Let's go
欢迎回家
欢迎回家  章鱼哥
Welcome home, Squidward
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
我们要让你今天变成最美好的一天
We're going to make this your best day ever
你最美好的一天可不该在外边虚度
Well, your best day's sure not going to be out there
要不要喝汤来庆祝你最美好的一天
How about some soup on your best day ever?
最美好的一天
喝汤了
Here we go
有点烫
It's a little hot
惨
很惨
我觉得不太适合拿汤来给他庆祝
I don't think soup is the best thing for him
最美好的一天
on his best day ever
要不要听音乐来庆祝你最美好的一天
How about some music on your best day ever?
这音乐可是用你的竖笛来演奏的哦
Played on your very own clarinet?
抱歉  我嘴巴有点干
Sorry, my lips are a little dry
音乐也不是很好
Music isn't best, either
不过我们留了样压轴好戏
But what is best is what we saved for last--
这大招肯定能成功让你最美好的一天
The one sure-fire thing to make your best day ever
成为最美好的一天
the best day ever
捉水母
Jellyfishing
这里是水母田
This is jellyfish fields
野生的水母们在这里遨游
where wild jellyfish roam
等待着我们来捉
just waiting to be captured
不对  章鱼哥
No, no, squid
到这来
over here
我知道你急不可耐
I know you're eager
可你连网都还没有呢
but you don't even have your net
派大星  帮他准备一下
Patrick, fix him up
我去给他找个范例
while I find him a good specimen
用手把网抓紧
Firmly grasp it in your hand
把网抓紧
Firmly grasp it
这样应该成了
That ought to do it
前方有水母就位
There's one in position
各就位
Ready
预备
Set
开始
Go
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squid
你能行
You got it
加油  章鱼
Go, squid
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squidder
对  您能行
Yes, you got it
加油
Go, go, go
捉住它  章鱼哥
Get it, Squidder
我们好像该给他示范怎么捉才行
I think we better show him how it's done
快看  章鱼哥在捉了
Hey, look, Squid's doing it
章鱼加油
Go, Squid
章鱼快捉
Get 'em, Squid
章鱼哥  干得漂亮
Squidster, you're doing it
加油  章鱼哥
Go Squid
这家伙不错
This guy's good
他是天生好手
He's a natural
对
Yeah
你能行
You got it
干得漂亮
You're doing great
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squid, go
继续努力  章鱼哥
Keep doing it, Squid
看看你都错过了什么
See what you've been missing?
对
Yeah
你能行的  章鱼哥
you got it, Squid
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squid, go
用那张网
Use that net
跟网合二为一
Be the net
对
Yeah
你感受到了  章鱼哥
you're feeling it, Squid
就这样
That's it
带过来  把它一路带过来
All the way, take him all the way
章鱼哥离成功就差最后六英里
The last six miles makes the Squid
加油
Go, go, go
你捉到了
You got 'em now
收入囊中
It's in the bag
今天是不是你最美好的一天呢
This is really your best day ever, isn't it?
派大星
Hey, Patrick
那个
Well
我觉得昨天进展很顺利  你说对吧
I thought yesterday went pretty well, don't you think?
我玩得很高兴
I had fun
我也是
Me, too
章鱼哥来了
Here comes Squidward
好
Great
章鱼哥  那个
Hey, Squid, how about that
最美好得一天怎么样
best day ever
明天永远都在
There's always tomorrow
我们为昨天的事情十分抱歉  章鱼哥
We're really sorry about
what happened yesterday, Squidward
我们要送你一份礼物
We got you a present
是那只水母
It's the jellyfish
就是昨天的那只
You know, from yesterday
你没在生气吧
You're not still mad, are you?
他还是很生气
Yep, he's still mad
痞老板
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
二号桌来一份蟹黄堡
One Krabby Patty for table two
蟹堡王
海绵宝宝  我没一整天的时间跟你耗
SpongeBob, I don't have the whole day
好的
Oui, oui
一份蟹黄堡  先生
Une Krabby Patty, monsieur
来个肉饼
There's les patty
快点  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
接下来  配料
Next, l'ingredients
来点芥末
Les mustard
能别装疯卖傻了吗
Will you quit fooling around?
我蟹黄堡在哪
Where's my Krabby Patty?
先等一下
Les hold on a second
快看
And voila
就在你鼻子底下
It's under your nose
你可笑死我了  海绵宝宝
You're killing me, SpongeBob
笑死我了
You really are
看看它  章鱼哥
Look at it, Squidward--
蟹老板送给裤头村老百姓的大礼
Mr. Krabs' gift to all of bikini bottom--
蟹黄堡
The Krabby Patty
好  给我吧你
Okay, give it to me
快点  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
别乱来了
Stop it
我发誓我什么都没做
I swear, I'm not doing anything
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
蟹黄堡闹鬼了
That Krabby Patty is haunted
站住  偷蟹黄堡的海盗
Avast, ye patty pirate
这不是鬼
This is no ghost
这是
This is
痞老板
Plankton
在偷我的财宝
Stealin' me booty
听我说  老螃蟹
Hear me, Krabs--
等我搞明白你蟹黄堡的秘方
When I discover your formula for Krabby Patties
我会让你破产的
I'll run you out of business
我上过大学的
I went to college
放我下来
Let me go
我会放你的  小矮子
I'll let you go, Squirt
坐飞碟去吧
on a flying saucer
回海之霸去吧你
Back to the chum bucket with you
你会付出代价的  老螃蟹
You'll pay for this, Krabs
海之霸
那是痞老板吗
Plankton, sir?
对  他多年来都在偷我的秘密配方
Aye, he's been trying to steal
me secret formula for years
可你就是偷不到对不对  小虫子
But ye haven't got it yet, have ye, bug?
行了
Okay
够了小子  没那么好笑
Enough, lad, it wasn't that funny
快回去工作
Get back to work
蟹堡王
好的蟹老板  明天见
Okay, Mr. Krabs, see you tomorrow
晚安  我的小子
Good night, me boy
海之霸
年轻人
Young man
对  到这来
Yes, over here
快啊  靠近点
Come on, boy, a little closer
近点
Closer
不要这么近
Not that close
你这可恶的呆头
You blasted barnacle head
我是说
I mean
嗨
Hi
痞老板
Plankton?
你想干什么
What do you want?
我只想谈谈
I just want to talk
我们应该算是朋友  对吗
You could say we're friends, right?
不对
No
老熟人
Acquaintances
不
No
我们都是无脊椎动物是吧
Well, we're both invertebrates, aren't we?
应该是吧
I guess so
看吧  这不挺好的嘛
You see, everything works out
我有样东西要送你
I have something for you
我一直把它放在我的秘密细胞区室里
I've been keeping it in my secret compartment
[ 细胞区室：具有界膜的细胞器总称
如叶绿体、线粒体等 ]
闪闪发亮
Sparkle, sparkle
一把黄金锅铲
A golden spatula
上面还刻着我的名字
And it's even got my name on it
这是礼物
It's a gift
朋友送你的礼物
A gift from a friend
朋友间就要互相赠送礼物
Friends give each other gifts
而且明天是我生日
And tomorrow is my birthday
知道我在这世上最想要的是什么吗
And you know what I'd like more than anything
in the whole wide world?
儿童垫高椅吗
A booster seat?
儿童垫高椅
Booster seat?
好啊
Hot dog
我是说  不对
I mean, no
我想要你  也就是我朋友在生日那天
What I want for my birthday from you, my friend
送我一个
is one of those
鲜嫩
tender
美味的
delicious
蟹黄堡
Krabby Patties
你想当我朋友
You just want to be friends
这样你就能把蟹黄堡弄到手
so you can get your hands on a Krabby Patty
而且明天也肯定不是你生日
And I bet it's not even your birthday tomorrow
我还以为你很傻
And I thought you were stupid
你绝对不会从我手上弄到蟹黄堡的
You'll never get a Krabby Patty from me
当了朋友也弄不到
Even if we are friends
弄不到
Never
我会弄到蟹黄堡的
I'll get a Krabby Patty
而且你会一个人亲手把它交给我
And you're going to hand-deliver it to me personally
你这低能的笨蛋
You weak-minded fool
晚安  小蜗
Night, Gary
海绵宝宝  你会是我的了
SpongeBob, you will be mine
字母表中字母妙  ABC
Letters of the alphabet, a, b, c
应该就在这附近才对
It should be in here somewhere
可是在哪呢
But where?
哪呢
Where?
马上就要开始玩完了
This will be the beginning of the end
笨脑子
Stupid brain
快点回来  你这头猪
Come back here, you swine
就这样了  大脑
That's it, brain
你要完蛋了
you're going down
好  好
Yes, yes
太好了
that's grand
现在开始我受过大学教育的详尽计划
And now, for my very elaborate
and college-educated plan
控制器
大脑
是时候要让你醒过来了
And now it's time for a little wakey-uppy
总控
已经早上了吗
Morning already?
我
I
我今天感觉有点怪
I feel a little funny today
好  好
Yeah, yeah
我控制住你了
I have you now
该吃营养均衡的早餐了
Time for a well-balanced breakfast
我心里想的可不是这样
This isn't what I had in mind
让我拿下裤子
Let me just grab my pants
看来今天我不穿裤子
I guess I'm not wearing any pants today
看来我也用不上门了
I guess I'm not using the door, either
再见  小蜗
See you later, Gary
应该吧
I guess
你说得对  小蜗
You're right, Gary
我有点不对劲
there is something wrong with me
章鱼哥
Squidward
醒醒
Wake up
我需要救命
I need some help
章鱼哥
Squidward
救命
Help
安静点  海绵宝宝
Be quiet, SpongeBob
救命
Help
海绵宝宝  你在搞什么鬼
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
我在跟你说话呢
I'm talking to you
海绵宝宝  海绵宝宝
SpongeBob, SpongeBob
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
闭嘴  你这滥竽充数的家伙
Shut your mouth, you mediocre clarinet player
滥竽充数
Mediocre?
你这自负过头的十八线小艺术家
You pretentious little insignificant artist
你的可悲创作所蕴含的价值
Your sniveling creations are worth less
比原生动物的排泄物还要低
than a protozoan's waste
我脑子肯定有问题
Something must be wrong with my brain
痞老板
Plankton
你算什么样的朋友
What kind of friend are you?
胡说八道
Nonsense
反正你也没喜欢过我
You never liked me, anyway
你甚至都不来参加我生日派对
You wouldn't even come to my birthday party
滚出我的脑袋
Get out of my head
别来碰我的大脑
Leave my brain alone
休想
Never
蟹堡王
打包外带怎么样
How about a little takeout?
不要  不行
Nope, no
休想
never
你骗不了我  痞老板
You can't fool me, Plankton
你就是想要蟹黄堡秘方
You want the Krabby Patty formula
海之霸
而且你会一个人亲手把它交给我
You are going to hand-deliver it to me personally
不不不
No, no, no
里面没人
There's no one here
用不着你说
Don't remind me
厨房
给我准备好  海绵宝宝
Brace yourself, SpongeBob
这是我的实验室
This is my lab
拉布拉多犬
而这是我的实验室
And this is my laboratory
我先前给你听过我的留声机了吗
And did I ever show you my record player?
我必须反抗
I must fight
不
No
好
There
有你帮忙事情就好办多了吧  朋友
you see how much easier it is when you help, friend?
觉得我的分析仪怎么样
How do you like my analyzer?
随便放个什么东西都能分析出成分
It tells the ingredients of whatever I put into it
海藻
50%海
50%藻
佩服吧
Impressed?
现在来揭露秘密配方的真面目
Now let's reveal that secret formula
这根小小的手指头把蟹黄堡带了回来
And this little piggy brought home a Krabby Patty
这根小小的手指头会帮我把它放进去
This little piggy will help me drop it in
有最后的遗言吗  泄密宝宝
Any last words, SpongeBob SecretPants?
我
I
我很对不起  我让蟹老板失望了
I just have to say I'm sorry I let Mr. Krabs down
我让全裤头村的百姓失望了
I let all of bikini bottom down
最糟的是
But worst of all
我让你失望了  娇嫩的小蟹黄堡
I let you down you delicate little Krabby Patty
你有着美味多汁
With your tasty, juicy
可口温暖又冒气的精华
scrumptious warm, steamy goodness
冒气
Steamy
我永远不会忘记你的高度秘密肉饼
I'll never forget your 100% all-secret patty
秘密地配着海底奶酪
secretly assembled with undersea cheese
腌椰菜
pickle
生菜
lettuce
番茄
tomato
洋葱
onion
全都在松软的海草籽面包之间蒸熟
all secretly steaming between
two fluffy seaweed-seed buns
好
Yes
快到爸爸这来
Come to papa
天啊
Oh, boy
痞老板
1%邪恶
99%热废气
倒霉透了
Well, this stinks
蟹黄堡  我们现在可以回家去了
Well, Patty, I guess we can go home now
海绵宝宝  那是我的蟹黄堡
SpongeBob, that's my Krabby Patty
还回来  你这浑身是孔的怪胎
Give it back, you porous freak
我命令你
I command you
我的蟹黄堡
My patty
不要
No
还是将就卖点薯条吧
I'll settle for some fries